[MUSIC]
[音楽]
Okay.
この線の勾配になります。この導関数項はこの線の勾配となります。しかしこの
So I have a question for you guys which is, how would you maximize recall?
みなさんに質問です。 どうすれば再現率を最大化できますか？
Remember recall.
再現率について 思い出してみましょう。
We just look at the magenta squares.
マゼンダの四角だけを見ます。
We look at the liked items.
気に入ったアイテムを見ます。
And we measure how many of my liked items were actually retrieved or
そして、気に入ったアイテムが どれだけ取得できたか、
actually recommended to me.
言い換えると、どれだけ 推薦してくれたかを測定します。
Well, as the title answers, there's a very easy way to maximize recall.
タイトルが答えになっていますが、 再現率を最大化する簡単な方法があります。
Just recommend everything.
単純に、全部推薦してしまえばいいのです。
If you recommend everything,
全部推薦してしまえば、
you're guaranteed to recommend the products that I like.
私の好きな商品が必ず推薦されます。
So in this case what would recall be?
では、このケースでは、 再現率は幾つになるでしょうか？
It would just be 1, because all 5 of the products I liked were recommended.
1になるでしょう。なぜなら、 お気に入りの商品が5個全部推薦されたからです。
So this is because there are 5 out of 5 products recommended.
5個中5個の商品が推薦されたからです。
But what's the resulting precision of doing this?
しかし、こうすると、 適合率はどうなるでしょうか？
Well, it can actually be arbitrarily small.
実は、任意の小さい値となりえます。
Because if you have tons and tons and tons of products out there, and
なぜなら、何千何万何億もの商品が 巷にあって、
if I like only a very, very small number of them,
私がその中のごく僅かしか 気に入らなかったら、
then if you recommend everything, I'm gonna have very small precision.
全部を推薦されたら、 適合率は非常に小さくなります。
So let's just say this is small and maybe very small.
このため、まあ、小さい、 おそらく非常に小さい数になります。
So that's not really a great strategy.
これはあまり良い戦略とは言えません。
On the other hand, what would be the optimal recommender?
では、最適化されたレコメンダーとは どのようなものでしょうか？
What's the best recommender you can imagine?
皆さんが想像する最高のレコメンダーとは
Well, the best recommender is one that recommends all
最高のレコメンダーとは、 お気に入りの商品を全て推薦するけど、
the products I like but only the products I like.
お気に入りの商品しか推薦しない というものです。
So everything that was not liked was never shown by the recommender.
つまり、気に入らないものは レコメンダーは一切見せません。
So that would be great.
これは素晴らしいでしょう。
No wasted effort,
無駄な努力なしに、
capture everything I like, gonna make lots of money with this recommender system.
好きなもの、たくさんのお金を稼げるものを、 このレコメンド・システウは全部拾ってきてくれます。
What's the precision and recall?
適合率と再現率は？
Both are 1 in this case.
このケースでは、両方1です。
And you can go through and
検証して確かめてみると良いでしょう。
verify that using the equations from the previous slides.
先のスライドに載っている 方程式が使えます。
[MUSIC]
[音楽]